# 二伯的番茄牛肉来了
Here it comes - Er Bai's Beef and Tomato!
# 第一步 焯牛肉 牛腩更好
First, blanch the beef. Beef brisket is better
# 凉水下锅
Blanch with cold water
# 千万别用热水去焯
Never use hot water
# 搁两根葱稍微去去腥味
Add some green onion to remove the odor
# 姜可以多搁点
You may add more ginger
# 老饭骨的黄酒我们来一点
Add some Lao Fan Gu's Huangjiu rice wine
# 这个沫子要及时撇出
Remove the scum immediately
# 你要不把它撇出来
If you don't remove it now
# 它一会滚到肉上去了
It's gonna stick to the meat later
# 以前大爷在清汤的时候
Previously when Da Ye was 'cleaning' the broth
# 为什么要砸一下
Why did he 'za' (add cold water into) the broth?
# 因为外边一紧了以后
Since if the outer surface of the meat shrinks
# 这沫子还没出来 锁死了
The scum will stay inside. Locked in the meat
# 这砸一下它又张开了
By adding cold water, (the surface) opens again
# 是吧 你看大爷又砸一回
Right? Look, Da Ye is adding water again
# 它又出来了 反复的砸
More scum is coming out. Add cold water repeatedly
# 我们这时候可以下个大料
We can add a star anise now
# 把这肉煮一会
Boil it with the meat for a while
# 一个两个都没关系
One or two, both ok
# 就是说肉多两个也没问题
You may add two (star anise) if you have more meat
# 你看你闻到料香味了吧
You can smell the aroma now, right?
# 这时候大料就扔出去
Now, pick out the star anise
# 就不能要了 再要这味就进去了
We don't need it anymore. Otherwise the flavor gets in
# 你看汤清
Look. The broth is clear
# 这样我们就捞出来
Pick it out now
# 料就不要了 搁一边去
Don't need the star anise now. Put it aside
# 这就行了
Done
# 咱是不是该压了师父 该压
-Should we use the pressure cooker now, master? -Yes
# 跟着我们就下一些料
Then, add some ingredients
# 一根芹菜 芹菜段
A celery. Cut into sections
# 然后洋葱
Then onion
# 胡萝卜再来一根
One carrot
# 两片香叶
Two bay leaves
# 来一个丁香 一到两个
One clove. One or two
# 搁个辣椒
One chili pepper
# 别多了 多了就味太重了
Don't add two much. Otherwise it's too strong
# 压多久呢 压40分钟
How long? Pressure-cook for 40 minutes.
# 好了 40分钟到了
Okay. It's been 40 minutes now
# 大爷您看看这个 清澈见底
Look at this, Da Ye. Clear as you can see the bottom
# 这个时候我再把肉捞出来
Now pick out the meat
# 肉已经好了 现在开始调味了
Meat is done. Now start seasoning
# 黄油啊大爷 黄油增加香气
Butter, Da Ye. Butter enhances the aroma
# 我先煸葱头
Stir-fry the onion first
# 然后这个芹菜一块煸
Then stir-fry with the celery
# 葱头跟牛肉是绝搭
Onion matches perfectly with beef
# 再加上黄油 西芹
Plus butter and celery
# 这是我们根据
This is what we ...
# 从西餐改良过来的东西
adopted from western food
# 我们来一片香叶 有一片就够了
One bay leaf. One is enough
# 现在我们可以
Now we can
# 加上番茄酱
Add some tomato paste
# 番茄酱呢 起增色
Tomato paste improves the color
# 番茄沙司 来一点
Ketchup. Add some
# 番茄沙司 起增味
Ketchup enhances the flavor
# 西红柿 搁里边
Tomato. Put into the wok
# 鲜的番茄是增鲜 你看红亮
Fresh tomato enhances the umami flavor. Look, red and shiny
# 下一步我们就可以加上汤了
Next, add the broth
# 加上炖制牛肉的原汤 原汤原味
Add some broth from cooking the beef. Original broth, original taste
# 把这捞出来
Take this out
# 用粉碎机把它打碎
Crush it with a blender
# 牛肉汤都搁里边 都搁进去了啊
Pour the broth into the wok. All of it
# 大爷我把肉下里边了
Da Ye, I am adding the meat into the wok
# 肉入味
The flavor penetrates well into the meat
# 打好的搁进去 很细腻啊
Blended vegetables. Very creamy
# 把味道充分（融）进去了
The flavor fuses into the dish perfectly
# 加点老抽因为这颜色它发粉
Add some dark soy sauce because it looks pink now
# 加点盐
Add some salt
# 再来点糖
Then some sugar
# 来一点水淀粉
Add some slurry
# 勾点芡
Thicken the soup
# 牛油果配这个就是特殊的香气味道
The avacado produces a special aroma in this dish
# 二伯 的番茄牛肉来了
Here it comes - Er Bai's Beef and Tomato!
# 颜色红亮
The color is red and bright
# 再加点牛油果 大爷
Add some avacado, Da Ye
# 味道十分鲜美
The flavor is awesome
# 方法独特
The method is unique
# 整个要从头到尾要搁着大料
If we keep the star anise from the beginning to the end
# 就有大料味了
Its flavor remains in the dish
# 但是我煮了一会儿我拿掉了
But I took it out after boiling for a while
# 你看见没大料这味 一点没有
You cannot taste it at all
# 这是技巧 香味
This is a trick on the aroma
# 还有一个技巧在哪
Where's the other trick?
# 就是大爷这五砸水
Da Ye added cold water for five times
# 大爷可能砸了五回
He might have done it for five times
# 他这砸一回 我撇一回沫子
Once he adds cold water, I remove the scum
# 他通过砸的方法
By adding cold water repeatedly
# 实际上就把一次次的沫子
In fact, the scum
# 就彻底弄透了
is removed completely
# 你看这汤 清澈到底
Look, the soup is clear as you can see the bottom
# 这还倍儿鲜
It's very delicious as well